# Rajesh Shenoy

## Software Developer

portfolio: https://shenoy.github.io/port-folio/

Ph: 07956110811

Email: rajeshtshenoyone@gmail.com

### Profile

An enthusiastic professional who is seeking a new challenging career after many years of being in scientific research. I am hardworking and strive to achieve the best in all areas, and I am always eager to learn new skills and advance my career. As this is a huge career change I have completed several courses in Javascript. As a self motivated individual, I am keen to follow my dream within this new industry of becoming a Software Developer.

### Skills

- Javascript, HTML5 and CSS3 Extensive experience through bootcamps, freecodecamp, codewars and Codecademy
- Node.js, Express, MongoDB Extensive experience through Udemy Node.js certification
- React and Redux Extensive experience through Udemy Node.js certification
- Other programming skills: Vue.js, Docker, Heroku, Github, Python, C, Test Driven Development

# Courses and Certifications

- Aug Oct 2019 HTML, CSS, JAVASCRIPT Freecodecamp and Codecademy Javascript, HTML and CSS
- Oct Nov 2019 JAVASCRIPT CODING BOOTCAMP: Northcoders, Manchester, Fundamentals of Javascript 3 weeks: Testdriven Development, Pair Programming, Object Oriented Programming, Asynchronous functions
- Nov Jan 2020 REACT, REDUX, NODE.JS, EXPRESS,MONGODB through Udemy, online created several apps covering front-end and back-end development using React, Redux and a nature tourism company website using Node js, Express and MongoDB

# Work Experience

- 2017-2019 Research Associate at Institute of Integrative Biology, Liverpool
- 2016-2017 Research Fellow at National University of Singapore
- 2014-2015 Research Scientist at Sporegen Ltd, Egham
- 2012-2014 Research Associate at University of Cambridge
- 2009-2012 Research Associate at University of Warwick

### Education

- 2004 2009 PhD in Biological Sciences, National Univ of Singapore, Singapore
- 1998-2002 Bachelors in Mechanical Engineering, VTU, Belgaum, India.

# **PORTFOLIO**

View some of my recent work. https://shenov.github.io/portfolio/

REACT MOBX LOGIN SYSTEM



Dashboard with a login system

This is a React login and signup system which uses MySQL database hosted remotely. The login system uses MobX library. React renders the application state by providing mechanisms to translate it into a tree of renderable components. MobX provides the mechanism to store and update the application state that React then uses. Backend built using Node. is and Express. The dashboard has 6 components - Weather with geolocation, RSS News Feed, Sports, To do list using local storage, Photo uploading and a pie chart panel.



CORVID

#### Coronavirus infection data for UK

This app uses Node.js, Express and MongoDB, RESTful APIs, Chart.js, HTML, CSS, Semantic UI, libraries like Mongoose and Mapbox for location data. I have used the MVC model for creating backend. Data is created by making POST request through Postman to the API running on express. The app is connected to the MongoDB database where all the data is stored. I have used Pug as a template engine to render the data to tables. Charts are rendered using Chart.js. The app is deployed on Heroku.

VIEW APP



App to generate prime numbers

This app uses Node.js, Express, RESTful API for the backend server which is deployed on Netlify. The frontend is built using React, Material UI and deployed on Heroku as well. The React frontend uses Axios ajax requests to fetch prime numbers from the server and renders it on the frontend in a responsive interface. Docker was used to containerize the client and server and can be downloaded from github and run on a computer as well.

VIEW APP



Season Geolocation

This app uses geolocation provided by the browser. The HTML Geolocation API is used to get the geographical position of a user. Based on the location of the user, it shows the season in that location. Built using Javascript, React, Redux, Node.

VIEW APP



Blogging site

This app uses Node.js, React, Redux and ReduxForm. Redux-form is a great way of managing forms that are powered by Redux. It is a Higher-Order-Component (HOC) that uses react-redux to make sure HTML forms in React use Redux to store all of its state.



DOW30 STOCK PRICES

Stock prices chart generator

This app uses stock data provided by Intrinio. It fetches the data and generates a chart using React Sparklines Chart. Built using Javascript, React, Redux, Node.

VIEW APP

#### REACT WEBSOCKET CHAT



Chat site

App created using React Context, Hooks, Socket.io and Express. The React chat Dashboard component sends the users's chat to the Socket.io server running on Express. Once chat is received, it broadcasts the message to all the users which are accessing the socket server. The broadcasted chat is received on the Store component which has the socket.io-client. The reducer updates the State and chat message appears simultaneously on all the Dashboards.

#### VIEW REPO



VUE-WEATHER

Displays current temperature and humidity

Frontend is built using Vue js. Current weather data is fetched from Openweathermap API. It fetches the data based on a search item and renders temperature and humidity. The background image transitions based on the temperature of 16 degrees C. App is deployed on Netlify. Built using Javascript Vue.js framework and Node.js.

#### VIEW APP





Instrument Dashboard for Data Analytics

The app was built using React, Node.js, Material UI, AG-Grid and HighCharts. The app has mainly 4 components. The Multiselect component hidden behind a sliding drawer, Dashboard search component, AGGrid component and HighChart component. Redux hooks (useSelector() and useDispatch()) were used to create a centralized Store and action creators to save the search results from the multiselect and searchbar components. The State is passed on to the AGGrid component as a prop from the dashboard component.

VIEW APP



CITY-WEATHER

Displays weather forecast for 3 days in US cities

Frontend is built using React, Redux and Node.js. 3 day weather data is fetched from Openweathermap API. It fetches the data using Axios based on a search item and renders temperature, pressure and humidity using React Sparklines. App is deployed on Netlify.

VIEW APP